<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><items><item id="44337831"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=44337831</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45209081"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering</title></titles><titleaddinfo>13</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>927</volumenumber><volumename>XIII International Conference on Applied Mathematics and Mechanics in the Aerospace Industry, AMMAI 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>XIII International Conference on Applied Mathematics and Mechanics in the Aerospace Industry, AMMAI 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>VUTOPU</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>13th International Conference on Applied Mathematics and Mechanics in the Aerospace Industry, AMMAI 2020</confname><confplace>Alushta</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>13.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012014-012014</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Modification of Gaussian elimination: technique, high resolution seismic model for area of natural accumulation of gases</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1757-899X/927/1/012014</doi><edn>IGJRDE</edn><grnti>373100</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Smaglichenko</lastname><initials>T.A.</initials><authorid>59811</authorid><email>tasmaglichr@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Smaglichenko</lastname><initials>A.V.</initials><authorid>882266</authorid><email>losaeylin@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Trapeznikov Institute of Control Sciences RAS</orgname><orgid>257</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>117997</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Sokolova</lastname><initials>N.V.</initials><authorid>888673</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Sayankina</lastname><initials>M.K.</initials><authorid>994744</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><abstracts><abstract lang="EN">The modification of Gaussian elimination is described here as numerical method to determine the physically adequate solution of the linear equations system that is affected by complexity of the data error (measurements, parameterization et. al.). Other modifications and algorithms are mainly established to efficiently overcome calculating issues. In order to avoid influence of errors in the data the proposed technique selects a set of invertible sub-matrixes. Developing the Tikhonov regularization theory the regularized subsequence is determined for each unknown under consideration. Application of the method to local seismicity data derived high resolution areas and revealed that the hydrothermal field of high concentration CH4 and CO2 is surrounded by rock having high seismic velocity. Based on this result we conclude that nature protects the gas flow due to special structure, which is likely presented by dense basalt. Decrypt of satellite images shows that the zone of lowest elevation does not intersect this structure. Particularities of background seismicity are examined for the gas area being studied. Factors learned from nature experience permit us to formulate conditions to select a place for underground gas storage.</abstract></abstracts><supported>We wish to thank Prof. Wolfgang R. Jacoby (Mainz University, Germany) for help in promotion of new
approaches of seismic tomography, for fruitful discussion and useful ideas. Our thanks go to DAAD
foundation for support of part of the research conducted here. The research was carried out within the
framework of the state projects № AAAA-A19-119013190038-2, № АААА-А19-119101690016-9 and
№ 10.331-17.</supported><references><reference num="1">Lantéri, H., &amp; Theys, C. (2005). Restoration of Astrophysical Images-The Case of Poisson Data with Additive Gaussian Noise. EURASIP Journal on Advances in Signal Processing, 15, 643143 https://doi.org/10.1155/asp.2005.2500</reference><reference num="2">Paige, C. C., &amp; Saunders, M. A. (1982). LSQR: An Algorithm for Sparse Linear Equations and Sparse Least Squares. ACM Transactions on Mathematical Software, 8(1), 43-71. https://doi.org/10.1145/355984.355989</reference><reference num="3">Ogbuobiri, E. C., Tinney, W. F., &amp; Walker, J. W. (1970). Sparsity-directed decomposition for Gaussian elimination on matrices. IEEE Transactions on Power Apparatus and Systems, (1), 141-150.</reference><reference num="4">Skala, V. (2013). Modified Gaussian elimination without division operations. AIP Conference Proceedings, 1558, 1936-1939. https://doi.org/10.1063/1.4825912</reference><reference num="5">Tikhonov, A. N. (1965). On incorrect problems of linear algebra and a stable method for their solution. Soviet Mathematics Doklady, 163 (3), 591-594.</reference><reference num="6">Anconelli, B., Bertero, M., Boccacci, P., Carbillet, M., &amp; Lanteri, H. (2007). Iterative methods for the reconstruction of astronomical images with high dynamic range. Journal of Computational and Applied Mathematics, 198(2), 321-331. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cam.2005.06.049</reference><reference num="7">Smaglichenko, T. A. (2011). Modification of Gaussian elimination to the complex seismic data. AIP Conference Proceedings. 1389(1), 1003-1006. https://doi.org/10.1063/1.3637779</reference><reference num="8">Smaglichenko, T. A., Horiuchi, S., &amp; Takai, K. (2012). A differentiated approach to the seismic tomography problem: Method, testing and application to the Western Nagano fault area (Japan). International Journal of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation, 16, 27-41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2011.11.010</reference><reference num="9">Nolet, G., Montelli, R., &amp; Virieux, J. (1999). Explicit, approximate expressions for the resolution anda posterioricovariance of massive tomographic systems. Geophysical Journal International, 138(1), 36-44. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-246x.1999.00858.x</reference><reference num="10">Lévěque, J.-J., Rivera, L., &amp; Wittlinger, G. (1993). On the use of the checker-board test to assess the resolution of tomographic inversions. Geophysical Journal International, 115(1), 313-318. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-246x.1993.tb05605.x</reference><reference num="11">Scholten J., et al. (2000). Hydrothermalism at the Kolbeinsey Ridge, Iceland Technical Cruise Report PO 253, University of Kiel 22-43</reference><reference num="12">2017 Google Earth Pro 7.3.0.3832</reference><reference num="13">Sokolova N. V. (2019). Influence of hydro and litho dynamic flow on the character of modern erosion division of territories. International Research Journal, 10, 60-64</reference><reference num="14">U.S Geological Survey USGS Earthquake hazard program</reference><reference num="15">Metzger, S., Jónsson, S., &amp; Geirsson, H. (2011). Locking depth and slip-rate of the Húsavík Flatey fault, North Iceland, derived from continuous GPS data 2006-2010. Geophysical Journal International, 187(2), 564-576. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-246x.2011.05176.x</reference><reference num="16">Clauser C. (2006). Landolt-Börnstein, Group VIII Advanced Materials and Technologies 3 (Heidelberg-Berlin: Springer) Geothermal Energy Renewable Energies 480-595</reference><reference num="17">Antonov P. L. (1970). Results of the investigation of diffusion permeability of sedimentary rocks for hydro- carbon gases. Trudy VNIIYaGG, 8, 51-59</reference></references></item><item id="44544709"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=44544709</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="44482510"><titles><title lang="EN">E3S Web of Conferences</title></titles><titleaddinfo>Regional Problems of Earth Remote Sensing (RPERS 2020)</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>223</volumenumber><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>IUFMLP</edn><publisher>EDP Sciences</publisher><confname>Regional Problems of Earth Remote Sensing (RPERS 2020)</confname><confplace>Krasnoyarsk</confplace><confdatebegin>29.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>02.10.2020</confdateend></source><pages>03001-03001</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>2</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Fire-induced changes in soil and vegetation in the forest-tundra of Western Siberia</title></titles><doi>10.1051/e3sconf/202022303001</doi><edn>CKAHBC</edn><grnti>870000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Sizov</lastname><initials>Oleg</initials><authorid>602242</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Brodt</lastname><initials>Leya</initials><authorid>971910</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>University of Tyumen</orgname><orgid>549</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Tyumen</town><address>6, Volodarskogo, Tyumen, 625003</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Soromotin</lastname><initials>Andrey</initials><authorid>251756</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>University of Tyumen</orgname><orgid>549</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Tyumen</town><address>6, Volodarskogo, Tyumen, 625003</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Prikhodko</lastname><initials>Nikolay</initials><authorid>1045116</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>University of Tyumen</orgname><orgid>549</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Tyumen</town><address>6, Volodarskogo, Tyumen, 625003</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Heim</lastname><initials>Ramona</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>University of Muenster</orgname><country>DEU</country><town>Muenster</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><abstracts><abstract lang="EN">Wildfires are one of the main factors for landscape change in tundra ecosystems. In the absence of external mechanical impacts, tundra plant communities are relatively stable, even in the face of climatic changes. In our study, lichen cover was degraded on burnt tundra sites, which increased the permafrost thaw depth from 100 to 190 cm. In old fire scars (burnt 1980 – 1990) of the forest-tundra, vegetation cover was dominated by trees and shrubs. The soil temperature on burnt forest-tundra sites was higher in comparison to conditions of the unburnt control sites and permafrost was was not found at a depth of 2-2,3m. Dynamics of the Normalized Difference Vegetation index (NDVI) from 1986-2020 reveal that immediately after fires, vegetation recovered and biomass increased due to the development of Betula nana shrubs. In old fire scars of the forest-tundra (burnt 1980-1990), a significant increase in NDVI values was evident, in contrast to the unburnt tundra vegetation where this trend was less pronounced. We conclude that "greening" in the north of Western Siberia may occur due to fire-induced transformation processes. The role of wildfires in the advance of the treeline to the north, driven by climate change and active economic development of the Arctic, will gradually increase in future.</abstract></abstracts><supported>.his study was funded by RFOR according to the research proAect Oelmont Forum proAect 162F 3ERU3.</supported><references><reference num="1">I. Nitze, G. Grosse, B.M. Jones, V.E. Romanovsky, J. Boike. Remote sensing quantifies widespread abundance of permafrost region disturbances across the Arctic and Subarctic, Nature Communications, Vol. 9 No. 1, pp. 1-11 (2018) [CrossRef] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="2">A.V. Rocha, M.M. Loranty, P.E. Higuera, M.C. Mack, F.S. Hu, B.M. Jones, A.L. Breen, E.B. Rastetter. S.J. Goetz, G.R. Shaver. The footprint of Alaskan tundra fires during the past half-century: implications for surface properties and radiative forcing, Environmental Research Letters, Vol. 7, No. 4, pp. 1-8 (2012) [CrossRef] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="3">M.K. Raynolds, D.A. Walker, K.J. Ambrosius, J. Brown, K.R. Everett, M. Kanevskiy, G.P. Kofinas, V.E. Romanovsky, Y. Shur, P.J. Webber/ Cumulative geoecological effects of 62 years of infrastructure and climate change in ice-rich permafrost landscapes, Prudhoe Bay Oilfield, Alaska, Global Change Biology. Vol. 20, No. 4, pp. 1211-1224 (2014) [CrossRef] [PubMed] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="4">E. Abakumov, A. Pechik, E. Chebyakina(Maximova), G. Shamilishvili. Effect of the Wildfires on Sandy Podzol Soils of Nadym Region, Yamalo-Nenets Autonomous District, Russia. Applied and Environmental Soil Science, Vol. 2020 (https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/8846005) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="5">P.D. Jones, D.H. Lister, T.J. Osborn, C. Harpham, M. Salmon, C.P. Morice. Hemispheric and large-scale land-surface air temperature variations: An extensive revision and an update to 2010, Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, Vol. 117, No. D5, pp. 1-29 (2012) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="6">J.A. Sobrino, Y. Julien, S. Garcia-Monteiro. Surface Temperature of the Planet Earth from Satellite Data, Remote Sensing, Vol. 12, No. 2, pp. 1-10 (2020) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="7">M.C. Hansen, P.V. Potapov, R. Moore, M. Hancher, S.A. Turubanova, A. Tyukavina, D. Thau, S.V. Stehman, S.J. Goetz, T.R. Loveland, A. Kommareddy, A. Egorov, L. Chini, C.O. Justice, J.R.G. Townshend. High-Resolution Global Maps of 21st-Century Forest Cover Change, Science, Vol. 342, No. 6160, pp. 850-853 (2013) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="8">M. Shimada, T. Itoh, T. Motooka, M. Watanabe, S. Tomohiro, R. Thapa, R. Lucas. New global forest/non-forest maps from ALOS PALSAR data (2007-2010), Remote Sensing of Environment, Vol. 155, pp. 13-31 (2014) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="9">H. Epstein, U. Bhatt, M. Raynolds, D. Walker, J. Pinzon, C.J. Tucker, B.C. Forbes, T. Horstkotte, M. Macias-Fauria, A. Martin, G. Phoenix, J. Bjerke, H. Tommervik, P. Fauchald, H. Vickers, R. Myneni, T. Park, С. Dickerson. Tundra greenness, Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society, 2018, Vol. 99, No. 8, pp. 165-169. [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="10">E.A. Loupian, S.A. Bartalev, I.V. Balashov, V.A. Egorov, D.V. Ershov, D.A. Kobets, K.S. Sen'ko, F.V. Stytsenko, I.G. Sychugov. Sputnikovyi monitoring lesnykh pozharov v 21 veke na territorii Rossiiskoi Federatsii (tsifry i fakty po dannym detektirovaniya aktivnogo goreniya) (Satellite monitoring of forest fires in the 21st century in the territory of the Russian Federation (facts and figures based on active fires detection)), Sovremennye problemy distantsionnogo zondirovaniya Zemli iz kosmosa (Current problems in remote sensing of the Earth space), Vol. 14, No. 6, pp. 158-175 (2017) [CrossRef] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="11">I.V. Balashov, A.V. Kashnitskii, S.A. Bartalev, S.S. Bartalev, M.A. Burtsev, I.I. Vorushilov, V.A. Egorov, V.O. Zharko, D.A. Kobets, A.M. Konstantinova, E.A. Loupian, I.A. Saigin, K.S. Senko, F.V. Stytsenko, I.G. Sychugov, S.A. Khvostikov, T.S. Khovratovich. VEGA-Les: information system for complex monitoring of forests and hunting grounds in Russia. Sovremennye problemy distantsionnogo zondirovaniya Zemli iz kosmosa (Current problems in remote sensing of the Earth space). Vol. 17, No. 4, pp. 73-88 (2020) [CrossRef] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="12">Atlas Yamalo-Nenetskogo avtonomnogo okruga (Atlas of the Yamal-Nenets Autonomous Okrug), Moscow: GUGK, 248 p (2004) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="13">I.S. Il'ina, E.I. Lapshina, N.N. Lavrenko Rastitel'nyi pokrov Zapadno-Sibirskoi ravniny (Vegetation of the West Siberian Plain), Novosibirsk: Nauka, 248 p (1985) [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="14">R.E. Hewitt, T.N. Hollingsworth, F.S. Chapin, D.L. Taylor. Fire-severity effects on plant-fungal interactions after a novel tundra wildfire disturbance: implications for arctic shrub and tree migration, BMC ecology, Vol. 16, pp. 1-25 (2016). [CrossRef] [PubMed] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="15">S.M. Landhausser, R.W. Wein, Postfire Vegetation Recovery and Tree Establishment at the Arctic Treeline: Climate-Change-Vegetation-Response Hypotheses, Journal of Ecology, Vol. 81, No. 4, pp. 665-672 (1993) [CrossRef] [Google Scholar]</reference><reference num="16">R.J. Heim, A. Bucharova, L. Brodt, J. Kamp, D. Rieker, A.V. Soromotin,.. &amp; N. Holzel. Post-fire vegetation succession in the Siberian subarctic tundra over 45 years. Science of The Total Environment, 143425 (2020) [CrossRef] [Google Scholar]</reference></references></item><item id="44997972"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=44997972</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="44997852"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>3</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1683</volumenumber><volumename>3rd Conference "Problems of Thermal Physics and Power Engineering" - Plasma Physics and Plasma Technologies</volumename><seriesnumber>3</seriesnumber><seriesname>3rd Conference "Problems of Thermal Physics and Power Engineering" - Plasma Physics and Plasma Technologies</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>KIVIVB</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>3rd Conference on Problems of Thermal Physics and Power Engineering, PTPPE 2020</confname><confplace>Moscow</confplace><confdatebegin>19.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>23.10.2020</confdateend></source><pages>032038</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Study of the phase behavior of n-pentacosane C&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;52&lt;/sub&gt;by optical method</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1683/3/032038</doi><edn>HDXPEK</edn><grnti>310000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuryakov</lastname><initials>V.N.</initials><authorid>152569</authorid><email>vladimir.kuryakov@gmail.com</email><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Dechabo</lastname><initials>V.A.</initials><authorid>36246</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>The work of V.N. Kuryakov was funded by RFBR, project number 20-08-00984. The work of V.A. Dechabo was funded by state task of the Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences (Project No. АААА-А19-119030690057-5).</supported></item><item id="44999265"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=44999265</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="44997129"><titles><title lang="EN">Saint Petersburg 2020 - Geosciences: Converting Knowledge into Resources</title></titles><titleaddinfo>Geosciences: Converting Knowledge into Resources</titleaddinfo><placepubl>Saint Petersburg</placepubl><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>POMQCD</edn><confname>2020 Saint Petersburg International Conference and Exhibition - Geosciences: Converting Knowledge into Resources</confname><confplace>Saint Petersburg</confplace><confdatebegin>06.04.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>09.04.2020</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Features of potential free gas accumulations distribution in the upper part of sedimentary cover of the arctic and subarctic seas</title></titles><edn>IWSSBF</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Bogoyavlensky</lastname><initials>V.</initials><authorid>276872</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas|National Research University</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Kishankov</lastname><initials>A.</initials><authorid>1057679</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas|National Research University</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="45001367"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45001367</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="44997210"><titles><title lang="EN">GeoBaikal 2020</title></titles><titleaddinfo>6</titleaddinfo><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>XJOHJV</edn><confname>6th International Conference GeoBaikal 2020</confname><confplace>Irkutsk</confplace><confdatebegin>05.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>09.10.2020</confdateend></source><language>RU</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Seismic interpretation during well planning, drilling, and production of complex carbonate reservoirs of the siberian platform</title></titles><edn>JTRPWR</edn><grnti>370000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Bibik</lastname><initials>A.N.</initials><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Institute of Geology and Development Fossil Fuels|JSC|«IGIRGI»</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Cherepanov</lastname><initials>E.N.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Institute of Geology and Development Fossil Fuels|JSC|«IGIRGI»</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Shuster</lastname><initials>V.L.</initials><authorid>484931</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="45049942"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45049942</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45046458"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering</title></titles><titleaddinfo>2, Mining, Production, Transmission</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>976</volumenumber><volumename>II International Scientific and Practical Conference "Actual Problems of the Energy Complex: Mining, Production, Transmission, Processing and Environmental Protection"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>II International Scientific and Practical Conference "Actual Problems of the Energy Complex: Mining, Production, Transmission, Processing and Environmental Protection"</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>LHSPEE</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>2nd International Scientific and Practical Conference on Actual Problems of the Energy Complex: Mining, Production, Transmission, Processing and Environmental Protection</confname><confplace>Moscow</confplace><confdatebegin>16.04.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>17.04.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012030</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Laboratory approaches to estimating and localizing restrained hydrocarbon reserves in depletion-mode formations</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1757-899X/976/1/012030</doi><edn>GLBPOM</edn><grnti>385300</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Bolshakov</lastname><initials>M.N.</initials><authorid>778517</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3 Gubkin street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Skibitskaya</lastname><initials>N.A.</initials><authorid>143647</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3 Gubkin street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Marutyan</lastname><initials>O.O.</initials><authorid>909288</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3 Gubkin street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="45084672"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45084672</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45082252"><titles><title lang="EN">Proceedings of 2020 13th International Conference Management of Large-Scale System Development, MLSD 2020</title></titles><titleaddinfo>13</titleaddinfo><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>AXBKYZ</edn><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><confname>13th International Conference Management of Large-Scale System Development, MLSD 2020</confname><confplace>Moscow</confplace><confdatebegin>28.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>30.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>9247697</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>2</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Alternative 3D Tomography Methods and Their Applications to Identify Seismic Structure around the Hydrothermal Gas Field</title></titles><doi>10.1109/MLSD49919.2020.9247697</doi><edn>DDBMTC</edn><grnti>370000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Smaglichenko</lastname><initials>Tatyana</initials><authorid>59811</authorid><email>tasmaglichr@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Jacoby</lastname><initials>Wolfgang</initials><email>jacoby@uni-mainz.de</email><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>University Mainz</orgname><country>deu</country><town>Mainz</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Smaglichenko</lastname><initials>Alexander</initials><authorid>882266</authorid><email>losaeylin@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>V. A. Trapeznikov Institute of Control Sciences of Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>257</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS We wish to thank members of the Mainz University research group for preparing the seismic data base, and for hospitality. The work was supported in part by DAAD foundation. Our thanks also go to Boris Chigarev (Research Oil and Gas Institute RAS) for fruitful discussion.</supported></item><item id="45126922"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45126922</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45083104"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</title></titles><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>LWPUEG</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>26.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>29.10.2020</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Formation of an effective hydrogen storage in an aquifer and control of its parameters</title></titles><edn>FVYMRA</edn><grnti>440000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Azretovna</lastname><initials>L.A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Nabievich</lastname><initials>S.Z.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Pavlovich</lastname><initials>D.A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Sumbatovich</lastname><initials>E.Z.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>Interest in hydrogen as an alternative energy source arose as a reaction of economically developed countries to the oil crisis in the 70s. Soon, the United States adopted a program for hydrogen technologies development, it received regular financial support from the state. So, only during 2004 - 2008 time period 1.2 billion US dollars were allocated for those purposes, among them 720 million were intended for research and development. In recent years, the US Department of Energy's funding for this program has been evaluated at $ 120 million per year. Today, more than 20 countries already have similar programs (Mitrova, 2019).</supported></item><item id="45130251"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45130251</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45083104"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</title></titles><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>LWPUEG</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>26.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>29.10.2020</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Assessment of non-equilibrium phase behavior model parameters for oiland gas-condensate systems by laboratory and field studies</title></titles><edn>PKIMZL</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Tsagan-Mandzhiev</lastname><initials>T.N.</initials><authorid>678961</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Aglyamova</lastname><initials>A.I.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Danko</lastname><initials>M.Y.</initials><authorid>587786</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Tyumen Oil and Gas Institute</orgname><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="45130463"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45130463</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45083104"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</title></titles><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>LWPUEG</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>26.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>29.10.2020</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Complex phase behavior study of a near-critical gas condensate fluid in a tight HPHT reservoir</title></titles><edn>IOFWHC</edn><grnti>520000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Yazkov</lastname><initials>A.V.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>PJSC NOVATEK</orgname><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Gorobets</lastname><initials>V.E.E.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>PJSC NOVATEK</orgname><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Surkov</lastname><initials>E.V.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>PJSC NOVATEK</orgname><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Solovyev</lastname><initials>V.V.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>JSC ARCTICGAS</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Devyatov</lastname><initials>A.S.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>JSC ARCTICGAS</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="6" lang="EN"><lastname>Vokuev</lastname><initials>V.S.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>LLC NOVATEK STC</orgname><orgid>19298</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="7" lang="EN"><lastname>Filippova</lastname><initials>Y.A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>LLC NOVATEK STC</orgname><orgid>19298</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="8" lang="EN"><lastname>Ibadullaev</lastname><initials>P.O.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>LLC NOVATEK STC</orgname><orgid>19298</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="9" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="10" lang="EN"><lastname>Lobanova</lastname><initials>O.A.</initials><authorid>681229</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="11" lang="EN"><lastname>Yushchenko</lastname><initials>T.S.</initials><authorid>987645</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="12" lang="EN"><lastname>Cherneva</lastname><initials>N.Y.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="13" lang="EN"><lastname>Alekseeva</lastname><initials>Y.V.</initials><authorid>971965</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="45131700"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45131700</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45125166"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference 2020, CTC 2020</title></titles><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>DWGEJW</edn><confname>SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference 2020, CTC 2020</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>21.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>22.10.2020</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>27</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Drilling problems forecast system based on neural network</title></titles><edn>RHCMAR</edn><grnti>520000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Borozdin</lastname><initials>S.</initials><authorid>926259</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Arkhipov</lastname><initials>A.</initials><authorid>925717</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Dmitrievsky</lastname><initials>A.</initials><authorid>59816</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences|OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Eremin</lastname><initials>N.</initials><authorid>318881</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences|OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Chashchina-Semenova</lastname><initials>O.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences|OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="6" lang="EN"><lastname>Fitzner</lastname><initials>L.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences|OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="7" lang="EN"><lastname>Safarova</lastname><initials>E.</initials><authorid>1073107</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences|OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="8" lang="EN"><lastname>Sboev</lastname><initials>A.</initials><authorid>1045381</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>National Research Center Kurchatov Institute</orgname><orgid>174</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>The authors would like to thank management of the Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences for the permission to present and publish this paper based on the results of the project "Development of a high-performance automated system for preventing complications and emergencies during the construction of oil and gas wells on the basis of permanent geological and technological models of deposits using artificial intelligence technology and industrial blockchain to reduce the risks of geological exploration, including offshore projects "under the Agreement with the Ministry of Science and Higher Education of the Russian Federation on the allocation of a subsidy in the form of a grant dated November 22, 2019 No. 075-15-2019-1688, unique project identifier RFMEFI60419X0217.</supported></item><item id="45251802"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45251802</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45249290"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering</title></titles><titleaddinfo>2</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>921</volumenumber><volumename>II Scientific-Practical Forum "Oil Capital"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>II Scientific-Practical Forum "Oil Capital"</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>EFGBMU</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>2nd Scientific-Practical Forum on Oil Capital</confname><confplace>Khanty-Mansyisk</confplace><confdatebegin>21.02.2019</confdatebegin><confdateend>22.02.2019</confdateend></source><pages>012010</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">The formation of nanoparticles in the process of ultrasonication of the pure water</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1757-899X/921/1/012010</doi><edn>BXCPUK</edn><grnti>310000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Ivanova</lastname><initials>D.D.</initials><authorid>971149</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>D.I. Mendeleev University of Chemical Technology of Russia</orgname><orgid>364</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Miusskaya Street 9</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Gorbachevskii</lastname><initials>M.V.</initials><authorid>878003</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas (National Research University)</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><town>Moscow</town><address>65, Leninsky prospect, Moscow, 119991</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Novikov</lastname><initials>A.A.</initials><authorid>146951</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas (National Research University)</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><town>Moscow</town><address>65, Leninsky prospect, Moscow, 119991</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuryakov</lastname><initials>V.N.</initials><authorid>152569</authorid><email>vladimir.kuryakov@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3 Gubkin Street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>The work of D.D.I. was funded by RFBR, project number 20-35-80007. Electron microscopy and elemental analysis studies were performed by A.A.N. and M.V.G. and were funded by the Ministry of Science and Higher Education of the Russian Federation within the State Assignment (project 0768-2020-0007).</supported></item><item id="45282716"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45282716</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45249290"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering</title></titles><titleaddinfo>2</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>921</volumenumber><volumename>II Scientific-Practical Forum "Oil Capital"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>II Scientific-Practical Forum "Oil Capital"</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>EFGBMU</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>2nd Scientific-Practical Forum on Oil Capital</confname><confplace>Khanty-Mansyisk</confplace><confdatebegin>21.02.2019</confdatebegin><confdateend>22.02.2019</confdateend></source><pages>012009</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>2</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Permeability Alteration of Carbonate Reservoir Rock under Cyclic Geomechanical Treatment</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1757-899X/921/1/012009</doi><edn>LFIQVR</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Almetyevsk State Oil Institute</orgname><orgid>7655</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Almetyevsk</town><address>2, Lenina street, Almetyevsk, 423450</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Ibragimov</lastname><initials>I.I.</initials><authorid>1006242</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Almetyevsk State Oil Institute</orgname><orgid>7655</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Almetyevsk</town><address>2, Lenina street, Almetyevsk, 423450</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakiryanov</lastname><initials>R.A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Almetyevsk State Oil Institute</orgname><orgid>7655</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Almetyevsk</town><address>2, Lenina street, Almetyevsk, 423450</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Idiyatullin</lastname><initials>I.F.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Almetyevsk State Oil Institute</orgname><orgid>7655</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Almetyevsk</town><address>2, Lenina street, Almetyevsk, 423450</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Girfanov</lastname><initials>I.I.</initials><authorid>1117873</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>TatNIPIneft Institute of Pjsc Tatneft</orgname><orgid>2268</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Bugulma, Tatarstan</town><address>M. Djalilia str. 32</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="6" lang="EN"><lastname>Remeyev</lastname><initials>M.M.</initials><authorid>936839</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>TatNIPIneft Institute of Pjsc Tatneft</orgname><orgid>2268</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Bugulma, Tatarstan</town><address>M. Djalilia str. 32</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="7" lang="EN"><lastname>Mansurov</lastname><initials>A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>TatNIPIneft Institute of Pjsc Tatneft</orgname><orgid>2268</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Bugulma, Tatarstan</town><address>M. Djalilia str. 32</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>The results presented in the paper were obtained under the Research Contracts of ASOI and TatNIPIneft funded by PJSC Tatneft, and under the State Research Contract of OGRI RAS (topic AAAA-A19-119022090096-5).</supported></item><item id="45285029"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45285029</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45249290"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering</title></titles><titleaddinfo>2</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>921</volumenumber><volumename>II Scientific-Practical Forum "Oil Capital"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>II Scientific-Practical Forum "Oil Capital"</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>EFGBMU</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>2nd Scientific-Practical Forum on Oil Capital</confname><confplace>Khanty-Mansyisk</confplace><confdatebegin>21.02.2019</confdatebegin><confdateend>22.02.2019</confdateend></source><pages>012025</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Modeling of the development of the Vuktyl field hydrocarbon system in the depletion mode using a bench installation</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1757-899X/921/1/012025</doi><edn>MWWJQC</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Skibitskaya</lastname><initials>N.A.</initials><authorid>143647</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupsky</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Bolshakov</lastname><initials>M.N.</initials><authorid>778517</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuzmin</lastname><initials>V.A.</initials><authorid>804891</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Marutyan</lastname><initials>O.O.</initials><authorid>909288</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="6" lang="EN"><lastname>Volkov</lastname><initials>A.N.</initials><authorid>44129</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Ooo Gazprom Vniigaz</orgname><orgid>3966</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Ukhta</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="7" lang="EN"><lastname>Latishev</lastname><initials>A.A.</initials><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Ooo Gazprom Vniigaz</orgname><orgid>3966</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Ukhta</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="8" lang="EN"><lastname>Popov</lastname><initials>A.A.</initials><authorid>957724</authorid><email>rgu2006@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Ooo Gazprom Vniigaz</orgname><orgid>3966</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Ukhta</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="45456694"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45456694</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45442758"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering</title></titles><titleaddinfo>5</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>848</volumenumber><volumename>5th Interdisciplinary Scientific Forum with International Participation "New Materials and Promising Technologies"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>5th Interdisciplinary Scientific Forum with International Participation "New Materials and Promising Technologies"</seriesname><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>CKSODV</edn><publisher>Institute of Physics Publishing</publisher><confname>5th Interdisciplinary Scientific Forum with International Participation on New Materials and Promising Technologies</confname><confplace>Moscow</confplace><confdatebegin>30.10.2019</confdatebegin><confdateend>01.11.2019</confdateend></source><pages>012044</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>6</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Determination of phase transition temperatures (melting, crystallization, rotator phases) of n-alkanes by the optical method</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1757-899X/848/1/012044</doi><edn>WETRBG</edn><grnti>310000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuryakov</lastname><initials>V.N.</initials><authorid>152569</authorid><email>vladimir.kuryakov@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street Moscow</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas (National Research University)</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>65, Leninsky prospect, Moscow, 119991</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Ivanova</lastname><initials>D.D.</initials><authorid>971149</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>D. I. Mendeleev University of Chemical Technology of Russia</orgname><orgid>364</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>9, Miusskaya Street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Tkachenko</lastname><initials>A.N.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>Lomonosov Moscow State University</orgname><orgid>2541</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Leninskiye Gory, Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Sedenkov</lastname><initials>P.N.</initials><authorid>996671</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="5" lang="EN"><orgname>Moscow Pedagogical State University</orgname><orgid>924</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>1, Malaya Pirogovskaya street, Moscow, 119992</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>The reported study was funded by RFBR, project number 20-08-00984.</supported></item><item id="45908903"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=45908903</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45908021"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>9</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1730</volumenumber><volumename>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>FKRRMO</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</confname><confplace>Tinos Island, Virtual</confplace><confdatebegin>07.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012101</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Simulation of Time-Lapse Resistivity Logging during Two-Phase Well Testing in Petroleum Reservoirs</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1730/1/012101</doi><edn>QQYPAC</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Shishkina</lastname><initials>O.A.</initials><authorid>1122020</authorid><email>shishkinaolga.an@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Kovalenko</lastname><initials>K.V.</initials><authorid>345331</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Makarova</lastname><initials>A.A.</initials><authorid>908500</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="6" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeev</lastname><initials>D.P.</initials><authorid>608396</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="7" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeeva</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>1177993</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46512075"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46512075</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45908021"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>9</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1730</volumenumber><volumename>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>FKRRMO</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</confname><confplace>Tinos Island, Virtual</confplace><confdatebegin>07.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012105</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">About identifiability of oil and water relative permeability curves and reservoir heterogeneity through integrated well test study</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1730/1/012105</doi><edn>JJQQQC</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><email>ezakirov@ogri.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeev</lastname><initials>D.P.</initials><authorid>608396</authorid><email>anykey_dp@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Tsagan-Mandzhiev</lastname><initials>T.N.</initials><authorid>678961</authorid><email>ts-mandzhiev@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Alekseeva</lastname><initials>Yu.V.</initials><authorid>971965</authorid><email>avajul@yandex.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><abstracts><abstract lang="EN">Relative permeabilities (RP) play an important role in reservoir engineering. RP functions together with the permeability anisotropy coefficient predetermine waterflooding efficiency and oil/water ratio in production forecast. Traditionally multiphase flow parameters are estimated from core analysis data. But such measurements suffer from small representative elementary volume (REV) and limited characterization of reservoir properties. Therefore using core data in 3D reservoir modelling could lead to distorted description of actual flow conditions. Despite those functions (RP) could be history matched with assimilated production data, such a procedure would require long history of waterflooding. So the authors' idea is to apply integrated well test study to estimate the displacement efficiency and/or relative permeability functions at downhole conditions. Well testing is traditionally applied in reservoir engineering for single-phase reservoir parameters estimation. Our approach is extended to multi-phase flow and is based on data collection at well bottomholes and subsequent data assimilation in flow model.
In this paper we summarize both features of mathematical problem statement and identifiability of multiphase parameters through inverse problem solution, but also discuss 10+ -year experience in interpretation of two-phase well testing using our technologies. To estimate multiphase parameters, we have to jointly consider complex data of well logging and dynamic data of well testing. Both data sets are used in the inverse problem quality criteria, where the least squares method has been applied. Forward problem corresponds to a 3D multiphase fluid flow model in porous media. The latter consists of continuity equation with multiphase Darcy equation instead of moment balances. For data assimilation modern methods of optimal control theory were successfully applied. For all synthetic test cases real reservoir parameters were accurately recovered through the use of forward simulation data.
In order to estimate reservoir heterogeneity, we applied a single-phase model to get the ratio of vertical to horizontal permeability. Data of well self-interference testing were used for vertical permeability estimation. Depending on the depth of reservoir pressure perturbation, reservoir properties could be properly inferred from observations. Two other options of 3D interference testing using vertical and horizontal wells are also presented.
In other words, all the problems considered are identifiable, and the level of their correctness is completely predetermined by the amount and quality of observed data. And transition to digital (intelligent) oil-and-gas production and closed-loop reservoir management [1] provides a possibility to remove discussed restrictions and all inverse problems considered should be accounted as fully identifiable.</abstract></abstracts><supported>The paper was prepared as part of the State Research Contract of OGRI RAS (topic "Scientific
substantiation of new environmentally friendly development technologies for hydrocarbons deposits in
difficult mining and geological conditions on the basis of 3D computer experiments", No. AAAAA19-119022090096-5).
</supported><references><reference num="1">Zakirov E S, Zakirov S N, Indrupskiy I M, Lyubimova O V, Anikeev D P, Shiryaev I M and Baganova M N 2015 Optimal Control of Field Development in a Closed Loop SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference (Moscow, Russia,) SPE Paper 176642-MS https://doi.org/10.2118/176642-MS</reference><reference num="2">Zakirov E S 2007 Upscaling in 3D Reservoir Simulation (Moscow: Kniga i Biznes) 344 in Russian</reference><reference num="3">Kamal M M (ed) 2009 Transient Well Testing SPE Monograph Series 23 (Richardson: Society of Petroleum Engineers) 850</reference><reference num="4">Kremenetsky M I, Ipatov A I and Gulyaev D N 2012 Information Support and Technologies for Flow Modeling of Oil and Gas Deposits (Moscow-Izhevsk: Institute for Computer Research) 896 in Russian</reference><reference num="5">Zakirov S N, Timashev A N, Sevastianov O M and Akhapkin V I 1985 Deep Sounding of an Aquifer during Field Development Gas Industry 1985 2 in Russian</reference><reference num="6">Zakirov S N, Indrupskiy I M, Zakirov E S et al 2009 New Principles and Technologies of Oil and Gas Field Development Part 2 (M.-Izhevsk: Institute for Computer Research) 484 in Russian</reference><reference num="7">Indrupskiy I M, Zakirov E S, Anikeev D P, Ipatov A I, Fakhretdinov R N, Gulyaev D N and Klochan I P 2008 Evaluation of Relative Permeabilities at Downhole Conditions // Neftyanoe khozyaystvo = Oil Industry 2008 (5) 38-42 in Russian</reference><reference num="8">Zakirov S.N., Indrupskiy I.M., Zakirov E. S. and Anikeev D. P. 2002. New Approach Toward Wells and Formations Testing // Neftyanoe khozyaystvo = Oil Industry. 2002; (6) 113-5 in Russian</reference><reference num="9">Anikeev D P 2007 Identification of Reservoir Properties in Specialized Well Studies Technologies of Fuel and Energy Complex 2007 32-6 June in Russian</reference><reference num="10">Zakirov S N, Zakirov E S and Indrupskiy I M 2005 New Vision of Problems of 3D Oil and Gas Fields Modelling IV International Technolological Symposium "New Technologies for Reservoir Development and Enhanced Oil Recovery" (Moscow, Russia,) 79-85 in Russian</reference><reference num="11">Zakirov E.S., Tarasov A. I. and Indrupskiy I. M. 2003 A New Approach to Gas Well Testing and Interpretation of Its Results // Gazovaya Promyshlennost = Gas Industry 2003 61-3 in Russian</reference><reference num="12">Zakirov S N, Indrupskiy I M, Zakirov E S et al 2016 In-Situ Determination of Displacement Efficiency and Oil and Water Relative Permeability Curves through Integrated Well Test Study at Exploration-to-Pilot Stage of the Oilfield Development Project SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference and Exhibition (Moscow, Russia,) Paper SPE 181967-MS. https://doi.org/10.2118/181967-MS</reference><reference num="13">Zakirov E S 2001 Three-Dimensional Multiphase Problems of Forecasting, Analysis and Optimization of Oil and Gas Fields Development (Moscow: Graal) 302 in Russian</reference><reference num="14">Gill P E, Murray W and Wright M 1981 Practical Optimization (London: Academic Press) 402</reference><reference num="15">Yang P-H and Watson A T 1988 Automatic History Matching with Variable-Metric Methods 62nd SPE ATCE (Dallas,) SPE Paper 16977. https://doi.org/10.2118/16977-PA</reference><reference num="16">Alifanov O M, Artyukhin E A and Rumyantsev S V 1988 Extreme Methods for Solving Ill-Posed Problems (Moscow: Nauka) 285 in Russian</reference><reference num="17">Indrupskiy I M 2005 Parameter Identification for Fractured Dual-Porosity Reservoirs Doklady Earth Sciences 405A 1294-7</reference><reference num="18">Zakirov S N, Indrupskiy I M, Zakirov E S et al 2012 Well Test for In-Situ Determination of Oil and Water Relative Permeabilities SPE Russian Oil and Gas Exploration and Production Technical Conference and Exhibition (Moscow, Russia,) SPE Paper 162011-MS. https://doi.org/10.2118/162011-MS</reference><reference num="19">Zakirov E.S, Indrupskiy I. M, Vasiliev I. V et al 2016 Complex Well Test Study to Evaluate Relative Permeability Functions to Oil and Water and Displacement Efficiency in Conditions of Abnormally Low Reservoir Injectivity (Part 1) // Neftyanoe khozyaystvo = Oil Industry, (9) 56-60 in Russian</reference><reference num="20">Zakirov E. S., Indrupskiy I. M., Vasiliev I. V. et al. 2017. Complex Well Test Study to Evaluate Relative Permeability Functions to Oil and Water and Displacement Efficiency in Conditions of Abnormally Low Reservoir Injectivity (Part 2) // Neftyanoe khozyaystvo = Oil Industry, (10) 90-93 in Russian</reference><reference num="21">Zakirov S. N., Zakirov E. S., Indrupskiy I. M. and Anikeev D. P. Method for Well and Formation Testing and Results Interpretation Pat. RU 2213864 C2 Appl. 06.12.2001; Publ. 10.10.2003</reference><reference num="22">Zakirov S. N. and Zakirov E. S. Method for Well and Formation Testing and Results Interpretation for a Well Completed in Oil-Gas Deposit Pat. RU 2258137 C1 Appl. 29.06.2004., Publ. 10.08.2005</reference><reference num="23">Leibenzon L S 1947 Flow of Natural Liquids and Gases in Porous Medium (Moscow: Gostekhizdat) 244 in Russian</reference><reference num="24">Zakirov S.N., Indrupskiy I.M., Zakirov E.S. and Anikeev D. P. 2008. Consequences of Transition to the Effective Pore Space Concept // Neftyanoe khozyaystvo = Oil Industry (6) 105-7 in Russian</reference><reference num="25">Tsagan-Mandzhiev T.N. 2012. Comparison of Investigation Radius for Vertical Interference Test and Tests with Formation Testers // Georesources, Geoenergy, Geopolitics 2012 1 www.oilgasjournal.ru (in Russian)</reference><reference num="26">Indrupskiy I.M. 2008. Interpretation of 3D Interference Test Results Based on Sector Modeling // Geology, Geophysics and Development of Oil and Gas Fields 2008 37-41 in Russian</reference><reference num="27">Zakirov E S, Indrupskiy I M, Levchenko V S et al 2008 Vertical and 3D Interference Testing of Productive Formations VII International Technology Symposium "New Technologies for the Development of Hard-to-Recover Oil and Gas Reserves and Enhanced Oil and Gas Recovery" (Moscow, Russia,) 49-63 in Russian</reference><reference num="28">Bradulina O. V. 2008. 3D Interference Testing at Pamyatno-Sasovskoye Field // Geology, Geophysics and Development of Oil and Gas Fields. 2008; (12) 42-6 in Russian</reference></references></item><item id="46550663"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46550663</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="46788024"><titles><title lang="EN">E3S Web of Conferences</title></titles><volumenumber>258</volumenumber><volumename>Ural Environmental Science Forum "Sustainable Development of Industrial Region", UESF 2021</volumename><seriesname>Ural Environmental Science Forum "Sustainable Development of Industrial Region", UESF 2021</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>NQANJH</edn><publisher>EDP Sciences</publisher><confname>2021 Ural Environmental Science Forum on Sustainable Development of Industrial Region, UESF 2021</confname><confplace>Chelyabinsk</confplace><confdatebegin>17.02.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>19.02.2021</confdateend></source><pages>08019-08019</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Unconventional technology for sealing and PandA of wells for prevention of global environmental disasters</title></titles><doi>10.1051/e3sconf/202125808019</doi><edn>UJXLJH</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>S.N.</initials><authorid>150891</authorid><email>suzakow@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Klimov</lastname><initials>D.S.</initials><authorid>710603</authorid><email>seydem@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><email>ezakirov@ogri.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeev</lastname><initials>D.P.</initials><authorid>608396</authorid><email>anykey_dp@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><abstracts><abstract lang="EN">Many, if not all of the oil and gas fields under development, have leaking wells. There are a lot of so-called abandoned, ownerless wells. Subsoil users, by one way or another, make efforts to eliminate leakage in such wells. At the same time there are no universal and reliable techniques. The problem of well leakage is seriously increasing when wells are decommissioned (plugged and abandoned, PandA), and even more so when the development of the field is finished. The techniques of plugging and abandonment do not guarantee the integrity of the abandoned wells for centuries. Obviously, then the abandoned field would become the object of a local ecological catastrophe. As the development of all oil and gas fields is completed, the Earth will enter the era of the Global Environmental Disasters. In this article authors propose innovative techniques and technical solutions for sealing procedures and plugging and abandonment operations on wells.</abstract></abstracts><keywords><keyword lang="UN">abandoned wells</keyword><keyword lang="UN">disaster prevention</keyword><keyword lang="UN">disasters</keyword><keyword lang="UN">environmental technology</keyword><keyword lang="UN">petroleum reservoirs</keyword><keyword lang="UN">planning</keyword><keyword lang="UN">soils</keyword><keyword lang="UN">sustainable development</keyword></keywords><references><reference num="1">Ki-Moon, B. (2015) A New Era of Opportunity // The Jordan Times.</reference><reference num="2">Seredin, V.V., Pushkareva, M.V., Leibowich, L.O., Bacharev, A.O., Tatarkin, A.V., Filimonchikov, A.A.(2014) Geological environment changes during oil fields development in complex geological conditions. Neftyanoe khozyaystvo - Oil Industry, 12, pp. 153-155.</reference><reference num="3">Raikevich, S.I.(2007) Providing Reliability and High Productivity of Gas Wells. IRC "Gazprom" Ltd., Moscow</reference><reference num="4">Johnson, P.(2015) Abandoned Oil and Gas Wells Are Leaking Methane across the USA</reference><reference num="5">Paper # 2-25. (2011) Plugging and Abandonment of Oil and Gas Wells. Prepared by the Technology Subgroup of the Operations &amp; Environment Task Group, Working Document of the(NPC North American Resource Development Study Made) npc.org</reference><reference num="6">How Texas's Zombie Oil Wells Are Creating An Environmental Disaster Zone. The Guardian April 15, 2021</reference><reference num="7">Khalimov, E.M., Lozin, E.V. (2013) Secondary Development of Oil Fields in Bashkortostan.FGUP " VNIGRI ", SPb</reference><reference num="8">Kokh, S., Dekterev, A., Sokol, E., Potapov, S. The guardian Numerical simulation of an oil-gas fire: A case study of a technological accident at Tengiz oilfield, Kazakhstan (June 1985-July 1986) Energy Exploration and Exploitation, 34 (1), pp. 77-98.</reference><reference num="9">Gajdos, M., Kristofic, T., Jankovic, S., Horvath, G., Kocis, I.(2015) Use of Plasma-based Tool for Plugging and Abandonment. SPE Off-shore Europe Conference and Exhibition, Aberdeen</reference><reference num="10">Zakirov, S.N., Indrupskiy, I.M., Zakirov, E.S. (2009) New Principles and Technologies of Oil and Gas Field Development. Part II. Institute of Computer Research, Moscow-Izhevsk</reference><reference num="11">Šmigáň, P., Greksák, M., Kozánková, J., Buzek, F., Onderka, V., Wolf, I. (1990) Methanogenic bacteria as a key factor involved in changes of town gas stored in an underground reservoir FEMS Microbiology Letters, 73 (3), pp. 221-224.</reference></references></item><item id="46753570"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46753570</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45908021"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>9</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1730</volumenumber><volumename>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>FKRRMO</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</confname><confplace>Tinos Island, Virtual</confplace><confdatebegin>07.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012113</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Simulation of Pressure Build-Up in Oil Wells with Non-Equilibrium Gas Dissolution</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1730/1/012113</doi><edn>EJUWDP</edn><grnti>520000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Tsagan-Mandjiev</lastname><initials>T.N.</initials><authorid>678961</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Basova</lastname><initials>K.D.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46756308"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46756308</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45908021"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>9</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1730</volumenumber><volumename>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>FKRRMO</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</confname><confplace>Tinos Island, Virtual</confplace><confdatebegin>07.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012099</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>2</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Estimation of Parameters for Non-Equilibrium Phase Transitions during the Flow of Oil and Gas Mixtures</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1730/1/012099</doi><edn>ENWGOS</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Cherneva</lastname><initials>N.Y.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46759315"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46759315</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45908021"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>9</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1730</volumenumber><volumename>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>FKRRMO</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>9th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2020</confname><confplace>Tinos Island, Virtual</confplace><confdatebegin>07.09.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012100</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Estimation of Uncertainty of a Volumetric Reservoir Model and Optimization of Numerical Inversion in Well Log Data Interpretation</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1730/1/012100</doi><edn>BNNNLE</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Khismatullina</lastname><initials>E.R.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Leninskiy ave., 65</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Kovalenko</lastname><initials>K.V.</initials><authorid>345331</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Leninskiy ave., 65</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina str., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Samokhvalov</lastname><initials>N.I.</initials><authorid>1134643</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas 'Gubkin University'</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Leninskiy ave., 65</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina str., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina str., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46766158"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46766158</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="46750154"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>35</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1787</volumenumber><volumename>XXXV International Conference on Equations of State for Matter, ELBRUS 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>XXXV International Conference on Equations of State for Matter, ELBRUS 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>FSJXNY</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>35th International Conference on Equations of State for Matter, ELBRUS 2020</confname><confplace>Elbrus, Kabardino-Balkaria</confplace><confdatebegin>01.03.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>06.03.2020</confdateend><confsponsor>Russian Academy of Sciences (RAS),</confsponsor></source><pages>012021</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Estimation of the flux density of galactic comets in the Orion-Cygnus branch based on number of shield volcanoes on Venus, craters on Mars and marine basins on the Moon</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1787/1/012021</doi><edn>CLMSWP</edn><grnti>410000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Barenbaum</lastname><initials>A.A.</initials><authorid>150550</authorid><email>azary@mail.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkin Street 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Shpekin</lastname><initials>M.I.</initials><authorid>22569</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Kazan Federal University</orgname><orgid>198</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Kazan, Tatarstan</town><address>Kremlyovskaya Street 18</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46831213"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46831213</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="46824261"><titles><title lang="EN">E3S Web of Conferences</title></titles><volumenumber>266</volumenumber><volumename>Topical Issues of Rational Use of Natural Resources 2021, TI 2021</volumename><seriesname>Topical Issues of Rational Use of Natural Resources 2021, TI 2021</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>HFIMGJ</edn><publisher>EDP Sciences</publisher><confname>2021 Topical Issues of Rational Use of Natural Resources, TI 2021</confname><confplace>Saint Petersburg</confplace><confdatebegin>31.05.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>06.06.2021</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Problems of unconventional hydrocarbons sources on the example of the domanikites of the Timan-Pechora oil and gas province</title></titles><doi>10.1051/e3sconf/202126601004</doi><edn>MVPGHF</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Rostovshchikov</lastname><initials>V.B.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Department of PR MPI|Ukhta State Technical University</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Ukhta,Komi Republic</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Kurta</lastname><initials>I.V.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>University Administration|Ukhta State Technical University</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Ukhta, Komi Republic</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Sbitneva</lastname><initials>Y.S.</initials><authorid>1160650</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>Department of Serveying and Exploration of Mineral Deposits|Ukhta State Technical University</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Ukhta, Komi Republic</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Kolokolova</lastname><initials>I.V.</initials><authorid>1090961</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46836456"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46836456</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45083104"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</title></titles><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>LWPUEG</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>26.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>29.10.2020</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Assessment of non-equilibrium phase behavior model parameters for oil and gas-condensate systems by laboratory and field studies</title></titles><doi>10.2118/SPE-201956-MS</doi><edn>HMVTWP</edn><grnti>520000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Aglyamova</lastname><initials>A.I.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Danko</lastname><initials>M.Y.</initials><authorid>587786</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Tyumen Oil and Gas Institute</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Tsagan-Mandzhiev</lastname><initials>T.N.</initials><authorid>678961</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Tyumen Oil and Gas Institute</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="46840711"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=46840711</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="45083104"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</title></titles><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><edn>LWPUEG</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2020, RPTC 2020</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>26.10.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>29.10.2020</confdateend></source><pages>201999-MS</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2020</yearpubl><cited>6</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Formation of an effective hydrogen storage in an aquifer and control of its parameters</title></titles><doi>10.2118/201999-MS</doi><edn>DYUSCN</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Abukova</lastname><initials>L.A.</initials><authorid>138669</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>S.N.</initials><authorid>150891</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeev</lastname><initials>D.P.</initials><authorid>608396</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>Interest in hydrogen as an alternative energy source arose as a reaction of economically developed countries to the oil crisis in the 70s. Soon, the United States adopted a program for hydrogen technologies development, it received regular financial support from the state. So, only during 2004 - 2008 time period 1.2 billion US dollars were allocated for those purposes, among them 720 million were intended for research and development. In recent years, the US Department of Energy's funding for this program has been evaluated at $ 120 million per year. Today, more than 20 countries already have similar programs (Mitrova, 2019).</supported></item><item id="47515629"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47515629</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="46927005"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>6</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>1942</volumenumber><volumename>6th Interdisciplinary Scientific Forum with International Participation "New Materials and Advanced Technologies", NMAT 2020</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>6th Interdisciplinary Scientific Forum with International Participation "New Materials and Advanced Technologies", NMAT 2020</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>NIJJYL</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>6th Interdisciplinary Scientific Forum with International Participation on New Materials and Advanced Technologies, NMAT 2020</confname><confplace>Moscow</confplace><confdatebegin>23.11.2020</confdatebegin><confdateend>27.11.2020</confdateend></source><pages>012035</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Influence of ultrasonic treatment on kinetic of asphaltene aggregation in toluene/heptane mixture</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/1942/1/012035</doi><edn>JPJDSG</edn><grnti>310000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuryakov</lastname><initials>V.N.</initials><authorid>152569</authorid><email>vladimir.kuryakov@ipng.ru</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>This work was performed within the framework of the state task of the Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences (Project No. АААА-А19-119030690057-5).</supported></item><item id="47519939"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47519939</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47519001"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2021, RPTC 2021</title></titles><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>GRNMAK</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2021, RPTC 2021</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>12.10.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>15.10.2021</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Investigation of CO2 utilization processes on metal-containing fillers with generation of hydrogen and hydrocarbons</title></titles><doi>10.2118/SPE-206612-MS</doi><edn>TSQUXP</edn><grnti>310000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Garifullina</lastname><initials>C.A.</initials><authorid>1127117</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>ASOI</orgname><orgid>7655</orgid><country>irl</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Ibragimov</lastname><initials>I.I.</initials><authorid>1006242</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>ASOI</orgname><orgid>7655</orgid><country>irl</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Klimov</lastname><initials>D.S.</initials><authorid>710603</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>OGRI RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="6" lang="EN"><lastname>Sakhabutdinov</lastname><initials>R.Z.</initials><authorid>682731</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>TatNIPIneft</orgname><orgid>2268</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47520862"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47520862</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47519001"><titles><title lang="EN">Society of Petroleum Engineers - SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2021, RPTC 2021</title></titles><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>GRNMAK</edn><confname>SPE Russian Petroleum Technology Conference 2021, RPTC 2021</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>12.10.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>15.10.2021</confdateend></source><pages>206614</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Estimation of diffusion losses of hydrogen during the creation of its effective storage in an aquifer</title></titles><doi>10.2118/206614-MS</doi><edn>OUBQNN</edn><grnti>520000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeev</lastname><initials>D.P.</initials><authorid>608396</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Anikeeva</lastname><initials>E.S.</initials><authorid>1177993</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>RUS</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street, Moscow, 119333</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47531602"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47531602</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47202760"><titles><title lang="EN">Conference “INTERAGROMASH 2021”. Precision Agriculture and Agricultural Machinery Industry, Volume 2</title></titles><titleaddinfo>Conference proceedings</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>247</volumenumber><volumename>Precision Agriculture and Agricultural Machinery Industry</volumename><seriesname>Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems 247</seriesname><yearpubl>2022</yearpubl><isbn>9783030809461</isbn><doi>10.1007/978-3-030-80946-1</doi><edn>GEXGTA</edn><pagesnumber>1058</pagesnumber><publisher>Springer</publisher><confname>XIV International Scientific Conference “INTERAGROMASH 2021”</confname><confplace>Ростов-на-Дону</confplace><confdatebegin>24.02.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>26.02.2021</confdateend></source><pages>131-141</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2022</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Modeling Carbon Dioxide Injection to Improve ORF in Low Permeability Reservoirs</title></titles><doi>10.1007/978-3-030-80946-1_14</doi><edn>ITTPBM</edn><grnti>520000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Klimov</lastname><initials>D.</initials><authorid>710603</authorid><email>seydem@mail.ru</email><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina st., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Zakirov</lastname><initials>E.</initials><authorid>324542</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina st., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47545249"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47545249</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47543205"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>10</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>2090</volumenumber><volumename>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>BPXXSV</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>09.09.2021</confdateend></source><pages>012141</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Semi-Analytical Method for Accurate Calculation of Well Injectivity during Hot Water Injection for Heavy Oil Recovery</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/2090/1/012141</doi><edn>WQTLTB</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina str., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Bukatkina</lastname><initials>A.D.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas «Gubkin University»</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Leninskiy ave., 65</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>This study is a contribution to the research performed under the State Research Contract of OGRI RAS (topic AAAA-A19-119022090096-5).</supported></item><item id="47547477"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47547477</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47543970"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Earth and Environmental Science</title></titles><titleaddinfo>4</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>931</volumenumber><volumename>IV International Youth Applied Research Forum "Oil Capital"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>IV International Youth Applied Research Forum "Oil Capital"</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>PHKAZW</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>4th International Youth Applied Research Forum on Oil Capital</confname><confplace>Khanty-Mansiysk</confplace><confdatebegin>24.03.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>25.03.2021</confdateend></source><pages>012011</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Investigation of the physicochemical properties of magnetic nanoparticles: Size, magnetic properties, concentration</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1755-1315/931/1/012011</doi><edn>MUBMHD</edn><grnti>310000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuryakov</lastname><initials>V.N.</initials><authorid>152569</authorid><email>vladimir.kuryakov@ipng.ru</email><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkin Street</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Sergeev</lastname><initials>I.V.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>DNA-Technology</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Nauchnii Proezd 20, bld. 4</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Efanova</lastname><initials>O.O.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>DNA-Technology</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Nauchnii Proezd 20, bld. 4</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Zheludkova</lastname><initials>O.K.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>DNA-Technology</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Nauchnii Proezd 20, bld. 4</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47547728"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47547728</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47543205"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>10</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>2090</volumenumber><volumename>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>BPXXSV</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>09.09.2021</confdateend></source><pages>012139</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Adjoint Numerical Method for a Multiphysical Inverse Problem of Two-Phase Well Testing in Petroleum Reservoirs</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/2090/1/012139</doi><edn>FQKOVA</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Shishkina</lastname><initials>O.A.</initials><authorid>1122020</authorid><email>shishkinaolga.an@gmail.com</email><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>This study is a part of the research performed under the State Research Contract of OGRI RAS (topic AAAA-A19-119022090096-5).</supported></item><item id="47547838"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47547838</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47543205"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>10</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>2090</volumenumber><volumename>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>BPXXSV</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>10th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical Sciences, IC-MSQUARE 2021</confname><confplace>Virtual, Online</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>09.09.2021</confdateend></source><pages>012138</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Thermodynamic Analysis of Relaxation Model for Non-Equilibrium Phase Behavior of Hydrocarbon Mixtures</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/2090/1/012138</doi><edn>CQTHEU</edn><grnti>385300</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Gubkina str., 3</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Chageeva</lastname><initials>P.A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>National University of Oil and Gas «Gubkin University»</orgname><orgid>898</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>Leninskiy ave., 65</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><supported>This study is a contribution to the research performed under the State Research Contract of OGRI RAS (topic AAAA-A19-119022090096-5).</supported></item><item id="47547912"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47547912</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47543970"><titles><title lang="EN">IOP Conference Series: Earth and Environmental Science</title></titles><titleaddinfo>4</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>931</volumenumber><volumename>IV International Youth Applied Research Forum "Oil Capital"</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>IV International Youth Applied Research Forum "Oil Capital"</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>PHKAZW</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>4th International Youth Applied Research Forum on Oil Capital</confname><confplace>Khanty-Mansiysk</confplace><confdatebegin>24.03.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>25.03.2021</confdateend></source><pages>012012</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Distribution of the Initial Fluid Composition in an Oil-Gas-Condensate Reservoir with Incomplete Gravity Segregation</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1755-1315/931/1/012012</doi><edn>EUVOPL</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Kusochkova</lastname><initials>E.V.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Indrupskiy</lastname><initials>I.M.</initials><authorid>331900</authorid><email>i-ind@ipng.ru</email><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Kuryakov</lastname><initials>V.N.</initials><authorid>152569</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47742146"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47742146</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47737261"><titles><title lang="EN">Geomodel 2021 - 23th Conference on Oil and Gas Geological Exploration and Development</title></titles><titleaddinfo>23</titleaddinfo><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>ZPDACU</edn><confname>23th Conference on Oil and Gas Geological Exploration and Development, Geomodel 2021</confname><confplace>Gelendzhik</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2021</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Digital remote sensing technologies for studying objects of powerful gas blowouts on the Yamal peninsula using unmanned aerial vehicles</title></titles><doi>10.3997/2214-4609.202157120</doi><edn>MZWMHG</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Bogoyavlensky</lastname><initials>I.V.</initials><authorid>819136</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute The Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47744764"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47744764</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47737261"><titles><title lang="EN">Geomodel 2021 - 23th Conference on Oil and Gas Geological Exploration and Development</title></titles><titleaddinfo>23</titleaddinfo><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>ZPDACU</edn><confname>23th Conference on Oil and Gas Geological Exploration and Development, Geomodel 2021</confname><confplace>Gelendzhik</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2021</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>1</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Central laptev zone of gas seeps: Comprehensive analysis of seismic data</title></titles><doi>10.3997/2214-4609.202157116</doi><edn>RHMUWH</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Bogoyavlensky</lastname><initials>V.I.</initials><authorid>276872</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute The Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Kishankov</lastname><initials>A.V.</initials><authorid>1057679</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute The Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Kazanin</lastname><initials>A.G.</initials><authorid>975561</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>JSC «Marine Arctic Geological Expedition»</orgname><orgid>15297</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="47747093"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=47747093</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="47737261"><titles><title lang="EN">Geomodel 2021 - 23th Conference on Oil and Gas Geological Exploration and Development</title></titles><titleaddinfo>23</titleaddinfo><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>ZPDACU</edn><confname>23th Conference on Oil and Gas Geological Exploration and Development, Geomodel 2021</confname><confplace>Gelendzhik</confplace><confdatebegin>06.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>10.09.2021</confdateend></source><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Forecast of the distribution and thickness of gas hydrate stability zone at the bottom of the Caspian Sea</title></titles><doi>10.3997/2214-4609.202157114</doi><edn>AVHPFB</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Bogoyavlensky</lastname><initials>V.I.</initials><authorid>276872</authorid><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|The Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Yanchevskaya</lastname><initials>A.S.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|The Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Kishankov</lastname><initials>A.V.</initials><authorid>1057679</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute|The Russian Academy of Sciences</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="48131058"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=48131058</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="48129830"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><volumenumber>2131</volumenumber><volumename>Intelligent Information Technology and Mathematical Modeling 2021, IITMM 2021- Mathematical Modeling in the Socio-Economic and Informational Spheres</volumename><seriesnumber>4</seriesnumber><seriesname>Intelligent Information Technology and Mathematical Modeling 2021, IITMM 2021- Mathematical Modeling in the Socio-Economic and Informational Spheres</seriesname><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><edn>YZTGXL</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>Intelligent Information Technology and Mathematical Modeling 2021, IITMM 2021</confname><confplace>Divnomorskoe</confplace><confdatebegin>31.05.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>06.06.2021</confdateend></source><pages>042049</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2021</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Study of synthesis of hydrogen and hydrocarbons by mechanochemical activation of the surface of mineral rocks</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/2131/4/042049</doi><edn>JTQWPN</edn><grnti>524700</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Klimov</lastname><initials>D.</initials><authorid>710603</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute Russian Academy of Sciences (OGRI RAS)</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>3, Gubkina st.</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item><item id="48413951"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=48413951</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="48411294"><titles><title lang="EN">Improving Energy Efficiency, Environmental Safety and Sustainable Development in Agriculture</title></titles><titleaddinfo>International Scientific and Practical Conference</titleaddinfo><placepubl>London</placepubl><yearpubl>2022</yearpubl><doi>10.1088/1755-1315/979/1/011001</doi><edn>IRDYVA</edn><pagesnumber>193</pagesnumber><confname>Improving Energy Efficiency, Environmental Safety and Sustainable Development in Agriculture</confname><confplace>Saratov</confplace><confdatebegin>20.10.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>24.10.2021</confdateend></source><pages>012126</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2022</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Using of pyrolysis data in the analysis of the oil-and-gas prospectivity of a formation as part of a studies complex on the example of the Marcellus formation</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1755-1315/979/1/012126</doi><edn>AIUIFW</edn><grnti>380000</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Maende</lastname><initials>A.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Wildcat Technologies</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Weldon</lastname><initials>D.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Wildcat Technologies</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Bolshakov</lastname><initials>M.N.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Zaharov</lastname><initials>A.D.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="4" lang="EN"><orgname>FIANUM</orgname></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Marutyan</lastname><initials>O.O.</initials><authorid>909288</authorid><affiliations><affiliation num="3" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors><abstracts><abstract lang="EN">The work objective was an analysis for the petroleum prospectivity of a core from the Marcellus Formation of Western Pennsylvania, USA. In accordance with the investigation results, two sample groups were delineated based on TOC and S1free oil measurements of the analyzed core and the most prospective interval for further development was marked out. Core analysis on a Marcellus TST sequence overlain by undetermined sequence Marcellus core was done using pyrolysis and SEM XRF measurements together with GR (Gamma Ray), ChemoGR (calculated from Potassium, Thorium and Uranium), Porosity and PHIE (Effective Porosity) logging. Oil saturation was measured using both Classical Pyrolysis and HAWK- PAM methods. HAWK Petroleum Assessment MethodTM is advanced multiramp/multizone pyrolysis method that utilizes five zones using multiple ramp and isotherm routines assigned during a single sample analysis. A ramp rate of 25°C is utilized to generate five petroleum peaks - four on oil fractions and one on kerogen. The efficiency of the HAWK-PAM pyrolysis method is shown for determination of the sweet spot intervals that is particularly important for the development of hard-to-recover unconventional reservoirs like the Marcellus Formation in USA or the Bazhenov Formation in Russia.</abstract></abstracts><references><reference num="1">Wrightstone G 2009 Marcellus Shale - Geologic Controls on Production. AAPG Search and Discovery 10206</reference><reference num="2">Dow W G 2011 How Plant and Animal Remains Become Oil and Gas: A Geochemical Perspective. AAPG Search and Discovery 40830</reference><reference num="3">Jarvie D M and Baker D R 1984 Application of the Rock-Eval III oil show analyzer to the study of gaseous hydrocarbons in an Oklahoma gas well. ACS National Meeting 187 8-13</reference><reference num="4">Jarvie D M 2012 Shale resource systems for oil and gas: Part 1-Shale-gas resource systems.Shale reservoirs-Giant resources for the 21st century: AAPG Memoir 97 69-87</reference><reference num="5">Jarvie D M 2012 Shale resource systems for oil and gas: Part 2-Shale-oil resource systems.Shale reservoirs-Giant resources for the 21st century: AAPG Memoir 97 89-119</reference><reference num="6">Peters K E 1986 Guidelines for Evaluating Petroleum Source Rock Using Programmed Pyrolysis. AAPG Bull 70(3) 318-29</reference><reference num="7">Loucks R G, Reed R M, Ruppel S C and Hammes U 2012 Spectrum of pore types and networks in Mudrocks and a descriptive classification for matrix-related mudrock pores. AAPG Bull 96(6) 1071-98</reference><reference num="8">Buller D, Hughes S N, Market J, Petre E, Spain D and Odumosu T 2010 Petrophysical Evaluation for Enhancing Hydraulic Stimulation in Horizontal Shale Gas Wells. (Florence,Italy) 19-22</reference><reference num="9">Jarvie D M 2007 Unconventional shale-gas systems: The Mississippian Barnett Shale of north- central Texas as one model for thermogenetic shale-gas assessment. AAPG Bull 91(4) 475- 99</reference><reference num="10">Throw J, Boillot G and Winterer E L 1988 Diagenetic History of Cretaceous Radiolarians.North Atlantic Ocean Proceedings of the Ocean Drilling Program, Scientific Results 103</reference></references></item><item id="48424741"><linkurl>https://elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=48424741</linkurl><genre>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</genre><type>статья в сборнике трудов конференции</type><source id="48424021"><titles><title lang="EN">Journal of Physics: Conference Series</title></titles><titleaddinfo>5</titleaddinfo><volumenumber>2192</volumenumber><volumename>V International Scientific and Technical Conference: Metrology of Physical and Chemical Measurements, MPM 2021</volumename><seriesnumber>1</seriesnumber><seriesname>V International Scientific and Technical Conference: Metrology of Physical and Chemical Measurements, MPM 2021</seriesname><yearpubl>2022</yearpubl><edn>JZRFBL</edn><publisher>IOP Publishing Ltd</publisher><confname>5th International Scientific and Technical Conference: Metrology of Physical and Chemical Measurements, MPM 2021</confname><confplace>Moscow</confplace><confdatebegin>14.09.2021</confdatebegin><confdateend>16.09.2021</confdateend><confsponsor>VNIIFTRI,</confsponsor></source><pages>012032</pages><language>EN</language><yearpubl>2022</yearpubl><cited>0</cited><titles><title lang="EN">Design and metrological characteristics of native analyzers Photocor for measuring the particle size and zeta-potential of nanodispersed systems</title></titles><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/2192/1/012032</doi><edn>VUYZBP</edn><grnti>311500</grnti><risc>yes</risc><corerisc>yes</corerisc><authors><author num="1" lang="EN"><lastname>Deshabo</lastname><initials>V.A.</initials><corrauthor>1</corrauthor><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>st. Gubkina, 3</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Photocor Ltd.</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>2nd st. Enthusiasts, bldg 40, of. 24, 5</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="2" lang="EN"><lastname>Kosov</lastname><initials>V.I.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>st. Gubkina, 3</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Photocor Ltd.</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>2nd st. Enthusiasts, bldg 40, of. 24, 5</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="3" lang="EN"><lastname>Yudin</lastname><initials>D.I.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>st. Gubkina, 3</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Photocor Ltd.</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>2nd st. Enthusiasts, bldg 40, of. 24, 5</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="4" lang="EN"><lastname>Yudin</lastname><initials>I.K.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="1" lang="EN"><orgname>Oil and Gas Research Institute RAS</orgname><orgid>570</orgid><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>st. Gubkina, 3</address></affiliation><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Photocor Ltd.</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>2nd st. Enthusiasts, bldg 40, of. 24, 5</address></affiliation></affiliations></author><author num="5" lang="EN"><lastname>Ashikhmin</lastname><initials>V.S.</initials><affiliations><affiliation num="2" lang="EN"><orgname>Photocor Ltd.</orgname><country>rus</country><town>Moscow</town><address>2nd st. Enthusiasts, bldg 40, of. 24, 5</address></affiliation></affiliations></author></authors></item></items>